this problem
asks us to write a program that displays
a welcome message
but only after the user has entered the
correct password
we're going to define the password as a
constant in our program
if the user enters an incorrect password
we will continue prompting them until
they enter the correct password
so the first step here is to initialize
our constant
and set up a password
[Music]
we'll use the word secret
and we're going to include a variety of
uppercase and lowercase letters
although typically you want your input
validation for
user input to be case insensitive a
password is a different situation
and you do want your input validation
for passwords to be case sensitive
of course this is just an example for a
small exercise
and this isn't how you would handle
passwords in a real world scenario
so we know we want to prompt the user
we'll ask them to please enter their
password
we'll initialize a local variable
password try
and this is where we'll store the user
input
recall that we want to call chomp on our
user input
in order to remove the new line
character from the end of the string
so we're prompted for our password and
at this point i can enter
anything
[Music]
and our program will just continue on i
haven't enforced any input validation at
this point
[Music]
so we'll want to put lines 3 and 4
within a loop
so that we can continue to prompt the
user to input the correct password
if the password they input was wrong
[Music]
now how do we determine if the password
they input was correct
we can simply compare
[Music]
the string referenced by our password
try local variable
to the string referenced by our password
constant and this comparison here on
line six will return true or false
we can actually demonstrate that just by
[Music]
outputting the return value of that
comparison
and remember we've left our user input
as
case sensitive so i'll enter the word
secret
but because the cases of the letter do
not match our password constant
we're expecting a return value of false
[Music]
and that's what we see
this time i'll enter the password with
the correct case
[Music]
and our comparison returns true
so now we know how we're determining
whether or not the user entered the
correct password
[Music]
and if they do then we want to break out
of our loop
[Music]
if they've entered the correct password
and we break out of our loop
we'll display a welcome message to the
user
this time when i enter the correct
password i'll expect to
see the string welcome
[Music]
now if i enter something incorrect
i'm prompted again but there's no error
message telling me that it was invalid
so let's fix that
[Music]
will display a message to the user
telling them that the password they
input was invalid
[Music]
typically if you're going to continually
prompt a user for something
you want to tell them why that their
input was incorrect or invalid
now when i enter an incorrect password
the program tells me that my password
was invalid and then prompts me for
the password again
so this is a much more clear message to
the user
and we've achieved all the functionality
we want here
notice again on line five that we did
not call the string down case method
on the user input and that's in order to
preserve
a case sensitive functionality for
passwords